MARIEN VAN OVERBEK

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

I am a software engineer specializing in TypeScript and React. I have a strong background in creating well-thought-out design systems, seamless API integrations, and strong user experiences.

I prefer working in a team of senior front-end colleagues, while maintaining close contact with both designers and the API team. I enjoy working on a product that is actively used by many people.

CONTACT

+31 (0)6 509 64 655

cv@marienvanoverbeek.nl www.marienvanoverbeek.nl

EXPERIENCE

IO - FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT CONSULTANT

Mar 2024 - Current, Rotterdam

Reunited with the iO Rotterdam team as a React developer, I specialize in enhancing user interfaces and guiding clients to ensure they gain a solid understanding and control over their projects. I focus on tackling technical challenges and delivering scalable, user-friendly UI solutions.

TypeScript · React · Storybook · Design Systems · GraphQL

PAY. - SENIOR FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Sep 2022 - Feb 2024 (1 yrs 6 mos), Spijkenisse

PAY. is a fintech company that aims to make payments easier for everyone. At Pay, I developed a design system with micro front-ends for a maintainable setup, enabling quick, flexible front-end modifications, including admin portals, registration flows, and checkout screens.

TypeScript · Micro Frontend Architecture (Nx) · Mentorship

ENECO - FRONT-END DEVELOPER & TECH LEAD

Oct 2018 - May 2022 (3 yrs 8 mos), Rotterdam

Eneco is a Dutch energy company that supplies gas, electricity, and heat to consumers and businesses. As a front-end developer and tech lead at Eneco (contracted via iO), I acted as the product owner's technical ally, focusing on UI development for customer self-service features.

ACATO - SQUAD LEAD / LEAD FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Mar 2016 - Aug 2018 (2 yrs 6 mos), Den Haag

Acato is a digital agency that creates digital products for clients. At Acato, I focused on front-end product quality to ensure the company excelled in delivering exceptional user experiences across websites, apps, and other environments.

JavaScript · Design Systems · React · REST APIs · Team Leadership

RIVERFIELDS - ONLINE MARKETING CONSULTANT & WEB DEVELOPER

Feb 2014 - Mar 2016 (2 yrs 2 mos), Rotterdam

Riverfields was a solo venture I started to help clients with their digital products. At Riverfields, I focused on front-end development, CMS implementation and online marketing.

Solo Venture · Front-End Development · Online Marketing

ROCKYARD VOF - UX DEVELOPER

Sep 2012 - Feb 2014 (1 yrs 6 mos), Groningen

Rockyard was a small digital agency I co-founded with UI/UX designer Edwin Niejenhuis. At Rockyard, we focused on UI/UX design, front-end development and CMS implementation, creating digital products for clients across the country.

Duo Entrepreneurship · Front-End Development · JavaScript

BIJZONDER PLEKJE - FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Jun 2010 - Mar 2016 (5 yrs 10 mos), Groningen

Bijzonder Plekje is a platform that inspires people to discover unique accommodations. At Bijzonder Plekje, I focused on online strategy, web development, and enhancing website performance for higher conversion rates and increased online visibility.

Freelance Work · Front-End Development · JavaScript · Online Marketing

EDUCATION

HANZE UNIVERSITY OF APPLIED SCIENCES GRONINGEN

Bachelor of Communication, Web & Mobile Services Sep 2008 - May 2013

SKILLS

- Front-end implementation
- Quality assurance
- Leadership
- Communication